A Guide to the Papers of The Center for Nursing Historical Inquiry 1934-2001
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- CNHI: Fay Franklin Thomas-Vaden Papers 1939-1996, 2 boxes, .8 linear feet
  - Series 1: The Thomas-Vaden Papers
    - Medical College of Virginia S.O.N. 1987, 1995 (Box-folder 002-013)
    - Math - teaching materials 1930s (Box-folder 002-014)
      Re: Basic math review course.
    - UVa Development Office [n.d.] (Box-folder 002-015)
      Re: Post World War II development office publicity brochure, "Unique in the Republic."
- CNHI: White Caps, Virginia Baptist Hosptial School of Nursing 1985-2001, 1 box, .4 linear feet
  White Caps is the yearbook of the Virginia Baptist Hospital School of Nursing (Lynchburg, VA). Ms. Eleanor Garrett donated six editions of the White Caps: 1960, 1963, 1965, 1969, 1973, and 1974.
  Arranged by date.
  - Series 1: Yearbooks
    - White Caps 1960 (Box-folder 001-001)
    - White Caps 1963 (Box-folder 001-002)
    - White Caps 1965 (Box-folder 001-003)
    - White Caps 1969 (Box-folder 001-004)
    - White Caps 1973 (Box-folder 001-005)
    - White Caps 1974 (Box-folder 001-006)
- CNHI: The Helen Yura Papers, 2 boxes, .8 linear feet
  As a nurse, educator, and author, Helen Yura, Ph.D., worked for over thirty years to reshape and enhance the American nursing school curriculum. Two of her most important books are The Nursing Process and Human Needs and the Nursing Process. The library's collection includes Dr. Yura's c.v., a typed manuscript of her dissertation (1970, The Catholic University of America, D.C.), various typed manuscripts and reprints of her articles, and an assortment of nursing education conference booklets from the 1960s and 70s.
  The collection is arranged into two series: Series 1 contains items authored by Yura, Series 2 contains items about nursing.
  - Series 1: Items authored by Yura
    - Biographical Data 1984 (Box-folder 001-001)
      Re: Vita & citation.
    - Minutes 1965-1967 (Box-folder 001-002)
      Re: Catholic University of America.
    - PhD Dissertation 1970 (Box-folder 001-003)
    - NLN Memos 1973-1979 (Box-folder 001-004)
    - NLN Publications 1974-1975 (Box-folder 001-005)
      Re: 9 books/phamplets authored by Yura.
    - Articles authored by Yura 1971-1992 (Box-folder 001-006)
    - Manuscripts by Yura/Ozimek 1079-1988 (Box-folder 001-007)
  - Series 2: Nursing
    - Nursing Diagnosis 1963-1988 (Box-folder 002-001)
    - Nursing Process 1981 (Box-folder 002-002)
    - Leadership 1967-68 (Box-folder 002-003)
    - Nurse Staffing 1985 (Box-folder 002-004)
    - Registered care technologists [n.d.] (Box-folder 002-005)
      Re: Handwritten comments on report sent to Yura.
    - Nursing Education 1971-1986 (Box-folder 002-006)
    - National Commission on Nursing Implementation Project 1986 (Box-folder 002-007)
      Re: Proceedings: First Invitational Conference.
    - National Commission on Nursing Implementation Project 1987 (Box-folder 002-008)
      Re: Proceedings: Second Invitational Conference.
    - ANA Publications 1973-1984 (Box-folder 002-009)